This is my ultimate art...!
(デイダラ)オイラの究極芸術だ。
これから オイラは自爆する。
Now I will detonate myself.
《サスケ : コイツ…》
He's...!
死んで オイラは芸術になる。
With death, I will become art.
This never-before-seen explosion
will leave
今までにない爆発は この地に
今までにない傷跡を残し➡
a never-before-seen scar
on this land.
And...! My art will win
never-before-seen admiration!
そして オイラの芸術は
今までにない称賛を受けるだろう。
《トビ… 悪いな》
Sorry, Tobi...
Hmm?
In the midst of my admiration,
you will definitely die!!
オイラの称賛のなか
テメエは確実に死ぬ！
An explosion that will cover
a ten-kilometer radius...
半径10キロが爆発範囲だ。
You won't be able to get away!
逃げきれやしねえぜ うん！
さぁ 怯えろ…
驚嘆しろ！ 絶望しろ!!
Now, tremble with fear!
Be in awe! Despair!
Scream!
泣きわめけ！ オイラの芸術は…。
My art is...
(デイダラ)喝！ 爆発だ!!
An explosion!
Wha--?!
(トビ)なっ！
何だ あれは!?
What is that?!
(キバ)何だ!?
What the--?!
(パックン)カカシ あれは？
Kakashi, what is that?
(カカシ)この感じ…
あのチャクラは 暁の…。
This chakra...
It's that Akatsuki member...
(ヒナタ)な 何だろう…。
Wh-What could it be?
(ナルト)行ってみるってばよ。
(ヤマト)あぁ。
Let's go check it out!
Right!
Look!
《香燐 : サスケ… まさか…》
Sasuke... It can't be...!
I can't sense Sasuke's chakra!
《サスケのチャクラが感じられない！》
That's near our rendezvous point...
(水月)あの辺りは集合場所だ。
まさか!?
Don't tell me he's...!
Damn! It's just as I feared!
って！ その まさかじゃないか!!
That Deidara...
He blew himself up.
(ゼツ)デイダラのヤツ 自爆したな。
トビは どこかな？
Where's Tobi?
Probably dead...
He was within the blast range...
(ゼツ)巻き添えだな
あの爆発の中にいただろうから。
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
Disappearance
Deidara is dead.
(ゼツ)デイダラが死んだ。
In the end, he went out with a bang.
最後は己で大爆発だ。
Oh dear.
Another member has been lost...
(鬼鮫)あらら
またメンバーが減っちゃいましたね。
And I thought he was
pretty strong.
彼は 結構 強かったと思いますが。
で どっちにやられたんです？
So? Which one did him in?
Sasuke? Or the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki?
サスケか 九尾の人柱力か？
It was Sasuke.
サスケだ。 ただしね…➡
However...
サスケも死んだみたいだよ。
It looks like Sasuke is dead too.
Deidara took Sasuke down
with him, huh...?
道連れですか…。
You should feel grateful, Itachi.
(ペイン)感謝するんだな イタチ。
デイダラが厄介払いをしてくれたんだ。
Deidara did you a favor
and got rid of your problem.
Hmm... I feel like
we've forgotten something...
ん～ あと何か忘れてるような…。
Looks like Tobi is dead too.
トビも死んだみたいだよ。 デイダラのヤツ
見境なく爆発しやがった。
That Deidara detonated himself
without regard for his surroundings.
Ah yes, Tobi.
そうそう トビでしたか…。 しかし
あの逃げ腰が逃げ遅れるとは➡
It must've been quite a jutsu
if that chicken was unable to escape.
相当 たいした術だったんですね。
まぁいい。 あの程度の男なら
いくらでも補充は利く。
No matter...
He can easily be replaced.
The loss of Deidara, however,
is unfortunate.
デイダラは惜しかったが…。
I liked Tobi.
私は彼が好きでしたよ。
When it came to lightening the mood
in our rather gloomy organization,
陰鬱な この組織の場を
和ませる能力なら➡
Tobi was quite talented.
トビも たいした能力者でしたがね。
I'm going.
オレは行く。
せめて静かにデイダラを弔うとしよう。
I shall mourn Deidara's death in silence.
Then I'll mourn for Tobi.
だったら ボクはトビの弔いを…。
暇だな…。
You must really be bored, huh?
(水月)蛇の紋章が消えたら と…
When the crest of
the snake vanishes...
Then... I do this...
コイツをこうやって…。
Add a drop of Sasuke's blood...
サスケの血をちょいと垂らして…。
All right.
よし。
Summoning Jutsu!
口寄せの術！
S-So, this is Orochimaru's
Summoning Jutsu...
コ… コイツが大蛇丸の口寄せ マンダか。
Manda...
Even Orochimaru had trouble
controlling this guy.
大蛇丸でさえ手を焼いていたコイツを
どうやって…。
How did Sasuke manage to...?
ん？
I see. He used genjutsu...
《なるほど… 幻術か》
Whoa, you're a mess!
なんだ ボロボロじゃないか！
誰とやり合ったんだ？
Who did you fight?
You... had the nerve...
(マンダ)この… オレ様を…➡
to use me...
利用しやがって… このクソガキ…。
You damned kid...
Those eyes... you controlled me...
with those eyes...
その目…
その目で オレ様を操ったのか…。
I... of all... people...
このオレ様を…。
Oh-ohh, he's dead.
あ～ぁ 死んじゃったよ。
マンダって あの大蛇丸の
いちばんのペットでしょ？
Wasn't Manda Orochimaru's
favorite pet?
You ought to treat animals better...
動物は もっと大切にしなきゃ。
それに ムリやり幻術かけてさぁ。
And the whole manipulation
with the genjutsu...
There wasn't time to think.
I had no choice...
ギリギリだったからな…。
そんな余裕はなかった。
Found you!
(香燐)いた！
I figured you'd be here!
やっぱりここか！
Your chakra suddenly disappeared,
so I wondered what had happened...
急に チャクラが消えたから
どうしたのかと思えば➡
Did you transport yourself?!
飛んでたのか！
You hid yourself inside Manda,
マンダの中に入って➡
then used the Transportation Technique
to escape into another dimension...
時空間忍術で別空間へ
飛んで逃げた… のはいいけど➡
So why are you in such bad shape?
なんでそんなにボロボロなの？
Just before escaping,
we both got hit by the blast wave.
飛ぶ寸前に
マンダと一緒に爆風を受けた。
My opponent was one of the Akatsuki.
相手は暁だ。
思った以上のやり手でな…。
He was stronger than I expected...
Sasuke all cut up and bruised
is also hot...
《傷だらけのサスケも かっこいい》
とにかく少し休養をとらないとね。
In any case, he needs time to rest.
Right, Karin?
なぁ 香燐？
Ahem! How pathetic!
だらしねえ！
それでも大蛇丸をやった男かよ!!
And you call yourself the man
who killed Orochimaru?!
大蛇丸は もともと弱っていた。
それだけの話だ。
Orochimaru was already weakened
to begin with.
That's all there is to it.
(鬼鮫)まだ やみませんねぇ。
この時期に この地域で➡
It just won't stop.
It's strange to have this much rain
around here at this time of year.
こうも降るのは
おかしいんですが。
お体に障りますよ。
You'll ruin your health.
冷酷なあなたが
今 何を考えているのか➡
I don't know what someone as cold as you
could be thinking about right now...
それは わかりませんが➡
But from here,
you look as though you are crying.
ここからだと
泣いてるように見えますよ。
弟さんのことなら 残念でしたね。
It's too bad about your younger brother...
You are now the sole survivor
of the Uchiha clan.
これで うちは一族は
あなた一人になってしまった。
No.
(イタチ)いや…。
ん？
Hmm?
アイツは死んでない。 それに…。
He's not dead. Also...
どういうことです？
What do you mean?
The rain... has stopped.
(イタチ)雨が… やんだな。
Naruto!
(サクラ)ナルト！
Looks like it caught all our attention.
みんな気になって
駆けつけたようだね。
What happened?!
何があったんだ!?
There are signs that Sasuke-kun
was just here.
サスケ君が さっきまで
ここにいた形跡があるの。
アイツのニオイが
かすかだが漂っている。
It's very faint,
but his scent still lingers.
I also detect other scents.
それに いくつか
他のニオイも残ってる。
どういうことだ？
What does it mean?
From the damage to the terrain,
I'd say there was a battle here.
(シノ)この地形の傷跡からして➡
ここで 戦闘があったと
考えられる。
I knew it! One of the other scents
belongs to that fellow in town
やっぱりだ。
この 他のニオイのひとつは➡
町で嗅いだ
サスケのニオイと混じってたヤツだ。
on who I detected Sasuke's scent.
Huh?
Looks like there are others
traveling alongside Sasuke.
どうやら サスケの近くについて➡
一緒に行動しているヤツらが
いるようだ。 同伴者がいる。
He has a companion.
Then, back there...
じゃあ あのとき…。
It's probable that...
おそらく サスケは
小隊を組んで移動してたな。
Sasuke has formed his unit.
One of the five other scents belongs
to Deidara from Akatsuki.
他の５つのニオイのうち ひとつは➡
暁のデイダラと呼ばれていた男。
え… アイツは自爆して➡
Wasn't he the one
who self-destructed
and was transported to another dimension
by your jutsu, Sensei?!
カカシ先生の術で
異空間に飛ばされたんじゃ…。
It seems he faked
his own death to escape...
どうやら 自爆に見せかけて➡
逃げていた
ということのようだな。
The Akatsuki operate in two-man cells,
so there are three left.
で ヤツら暁は➡
ツーマンセルで行動するから
残りは３つ。
Sasuke is moving with
a four-man cell.
サスケは フォーマンセルで行動している。
Who cares how many there are.
何人だろうと関係ねえ！
Let's get moving and
trace Sasuke's scent!
さっさと サスケのニオイを
追うってばよ！
それが ダメなんだ。
We can't.
Huh? Why not?
は？ なんで!?
ニオイが ここで なくなってる。
The scent stops here.
どういうことだ!?
What does that mean?!
こういう場合は サスケが爆発で
跡形もなく消し飛んだか➡
Usually in a situation like this,
either Sasuke was blasted to bits
by the explosion...
or Sasuke used
the Transportation Technique to escape.
あるいは 時空間忍術で
飛んだと考えるのが普通だ。
Transportation Technique...?
時空間忍術？
(キバ)どうやら 後者のようだな。
It's probably the latter.
My sense of smell is keener
than a dog's right now.
今のオレは 犬以上に鼻が利く。
見つけたぜ サスケ！
I've found Sasuke!
《忍犬以上の鼻とは
成長したな キバ。
A nose that's sharper than
the ninja hounds...?
Impressive, Kiba.
Just what I would expect
from a member of the Inuzuka clan.
さすがは 犬塚家だ》
キバ 案内してくれ。
Kiba, lead the way!
Come, Pain...
(小南)ペイン 来て。 彼が来たわ。
He's here.
And... what of Sasuke?
で サスケのほうは？
いい感じだ。
He's coming along nicely...
写輪眼の力を
十二分に発揮していた。
He was using the Sharingan's power
to his fullest...
His eyes will surpass Itachi's...
あれは イタチ以上の眼になる。
The time has come.
He must be ready as well.
機は熟した。
ヤツも覚悟は決まっているだろう。
そう長くはないからな。
After all, he doesn't have much time.
じゃあ 九尾のほうは？
Then what about the Nine-Tails?
You hunt it.
As leader, failure is not an option.
お前が狩れ。
リーダーとして失敗は許さん。
"Inn Okoshi"
ヘッ
イタチをやるって言ってたくせに➡
Hah! You talked about killing Itachi...
こんなザマじゃ
しばらくは動けねえぞ。
You won't be able to move around
for some time in that condition!
ここんところ 歩きづめだったから
ちょうどいい。 休暇がとれる。
We've been moving nonstop lately.
It's a good chance to rest up.
テメエは休みっぱなしだったじゃ
ねえか。 この貧弱野郎！
All you've done is rest,
you feeble punk!
よし 終わりだ。
(水月)北アジトで➡
There, finished.
You didn't do a thing at
the northern hideout,
なんにもしなかったキミには
言われたくないね。
so don't start telling me
what to do now.
なんだと コラ！ テメエやんのか オゥ。
ああ やってやろうじゃねえか！
What?! Wanna make something of it?!
Then let's do it!
いいかげんにしろ。
Enough already!
水月 香燐。 それより
イタチの情報は集まったのか？
Suigetsu, Karin...
Have you gathered data on Itachi?
ボロボロのテメエが
偉そうに言ってんじゃねえよ。
You're in no shape to act so bossy!
暁ってヤツらの情報は
いくつかつかんだが➡
I've picked up some tips
about Akatsuki,
イタチについての
はっきりしたものはなかったよ。
but nothing specific
about Itachi himself.
ウチは ゼロ。
I got zero.
ただ ヤツらは ある特定の人物➡
Seems they're targeting
specific people though...
特別なチャクラを持つ者たちを
狙っているようだ。
People with special chakra.
特別なチャクラ。
Special chakra...?
(重吾)オレは動物に語りかけ
暁のアジトをいくつか把握した。
I did some talking to animals and
located a number of Akatsuki hideouts.
その周辺では いつも大きく
イヤなチャクラを感じるらしい。
It seems they always sense
a powerful, unpleasant chakra
around each area.
動物たちは そう言ってる。
That's what the animals have told me.
へぇ 低能な動物たちも
チャクラを感じ取ることができるのか。
Wow, even simpleminded animals
can sense chakra, eh...?
いや 低能だからこそか。
まるで香燐みたいだね。
Or maybe it's because
they're simpleminded...
Just like you Karin!
っだと テメエ！
What did you say, you jerk?!
水月 テメエ 今度という今度は
絶対許さねえ！
Suigetsu! This time,
you're not getting away with it!
(水月)おい ちょっ… 待て。 おい。
Hey... W-Wait... hey!
殺す。 殺したい。
Kill... I want to kill...
- Huh?
- Huh?!
うぉ～っ！
"Inn Okoshi"
うぉ～。
やばい。 重吾の殺人衝動が。
Shoot! Jugo's killing impulse is loose!
サスケ 早くしろ。
落ち着け 重吾。
Sasuke! Hurry it--!
Calm down, Jugo.
ハァ ハァ。
す すまない。
S-Sorry...
香燐が悪いんだぞ
ギャーギャーと騒いで。
It's your fault, Karin.
Screaming and making such a fuss.
あぁ？ お前だって。
What? You too...
香燐 キミは そうやって
ボクを挑発して➡
You constantly try to provoke me, Karin.
何を企んでるんだい？
What are you up to?
前にも言ったと思うけど➡
I've already told you.
自分の目的のためにも
サスケから離れるつもりはないよ。
I don't intend to leave Sasuke
for my own reasons.
べ 別に ウチは
なにも企んでるわけじゃなくて➡
I-I'm not up to anything.
純粋に 水月 お前の気持を…。
I'm just trying to test your...
オレには… オレには サスケが必要だ。
I... I need Sasuke.
君麻呂の代わりになるのは…
サスケだけなんだ。
The only one who can
replace Kimimaro... is Sasuke.
サスケは オレの檻になると
言ってくれた。
Sasuke said he would
become my cage...
さっきのように オレの衝動を
止められるのは➡
Right now, only Sasuke can
stop my urges,
今は サスケしかいない。
like he did earlier...
でもね コイツはどうあれ➡
Still... I don't know about her,
but our cages are unlocked.
その檻ってヤツには
鍵なんてかかってないんだよ。
いつでも 誰でも抜け出せる。
なのにな…。
We can escape anytime we wish.
And yet...
間違いない こっちだ。
I'm sure of it. It's this way!
ヤツのニオイは 動きを止めている。
From his scent,
I can tell he's stopped moving.
どうやら 潜伏しているようだぜ。
It seems he's resting.
チャンスだな。
It's our chance.
《サスケ… お前への道が
つながったってばよ》
Sasuke...
Our paths have finally crossed.
うずまきナルト… あれは
ただのガキではなくなった。
Naruto Uzumaki...
He's no longer just a kid.
いまや たいそうな術を身につけ
仲間も多い。
He has now mastered
a formidable jutsu...
and has many comrades.
簡単には いかんぞ。
It won't be easy.
一撃で あの角都の命を
二つ削った。
He even destroyed two of
Kakuzu's lives with a single blow.
ターゲットをおそるべしとする
言葉は ちりに等しい。
To speak of the target as
a threat has no meaning before Pain.
ペインは 負けたことがないのだから。
He has never lost a battle.
フフッ… まっ それもそうだ。
Well, that's true.
話は終わりだ。
We're done talking.
他のメンバーに
残りの人柱力を急がせろ。
Tell the other members to hurry
with the remaining Jinchuriki.
わかっている。
I know.
いよいよだ… 我らが
目的を達成するのも あとわずか。
At last...
We are so close to the moment
of achieving our goal...
そうなれば すべてが
本来の形に戻るのだ。
Then everything shall be restored
to its rightful place...
写輪眼の本当の力が…
この うちはマダラの力が！
The true power of the Sharingan...
The true power of I,
Madara Uchiha!
また 空が鳴き出した。
The sky is crying again...
ペイン あなた…。
Pain... Are you...?
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
life always throws you curveballs and the reason of that is
yo kono yo wa hitosujinawa de ikanai sore wa naze nara
it's a test made by God so that's why it's quite hard
kamisama ga tsukutta tesuto dakara muzukashii nda
arts? science? or rather how about ethics?
bunkei rikei mushiro doutoku kimi nara kore wo dou toku
this is just like life so put your heart and soul into seriousness
kore wa maru de jinsei dakara uchikomu shinken ni
we worry ourselves lose ourselves and we keep asking ourselves questions
bokura wa nayamu mayou nandomo jibun ni toikakeru
we aren't one and relentesly persue our search for answers
hitotsu ja nai kotae sagashi gamushara ni oikakeru
keep your pants and shirt on even if you're unable to do it right now
ima dekinakute mo aseranaide awatenaide
you should believe in yourself and take it at your own pace
kimi no mai peesu de jibun shinjite yukkuri ikeba ii
the current me would tell me that if I was from the future
mirai no bokura nara ima no boku ni oshiete agerareru
you should keep pursuing it until your efforts change yourself
kimi no doryoku ga jishin ni kawaru toki made oitsuzukereba ii
Next Episode
I'm coming in, Tsunade!
Jiraiya? Did you learn anything?
I discovered the whereabouts
of the leader of "Akatsuki."
What?! Is that true?!
Tell me more!
(カプリコ)開け ベルパラソの狩人 サマグィ。
We'll use that information
to plan a surprise attack!
Now now, don't be hasty.
This isn't like plotting
a sequel to your novel!
レイラの娘を仕留めてこい。
We don't have the time to waste!
Haste makes waste.
Especially with the stakes
as high as they are...
Next time: "Twilight"
Twilight